<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site.
 It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content.
 You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another.
 This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site.

 To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps:
 1. Log in to that site as an administrator.
 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel.
 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list.
 4. Activate & Run Importer.
 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page.
 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users
    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an
    existing user on the site or to create a new user.
 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc.
    contained in this file into your site.
-->
<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2015-03-19 06:26"-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">
  <channel>
<title>Taking a one and one</title>
<link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 06:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
<language>en</language>
<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
<wp:base_blog_url>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>
<wp:author>
  <wp:author_login>jlericson</wp:author_login>
  <wp:author_email>jlericson@gmail.com</wp:author_email>
  <wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Jon Ericson]]></wp:author_display_name>
  <wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name>
  <wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name>
</wp:author>
<wp:category>
  <wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id>
  <wp:category_nicename>uncategorized</wp:category_nicename>
  <wp:category_parent/>
  <wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name>
</wp:category>
<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<image>
		<url>https://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title> &#187; Taking a one and one</title>
		<link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<item>
  <title>1 + 1 = 1</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/hello-world/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 16:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=1</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[The traditional blog contains two posts: the hopeful introduction that sparks some interest in the author and the followup a few weeks later apologizing for not updating more often.  I'm pretty sure when people wrote their intimate thoughts on paper, the pattern held.  But since diaries and journals never get published until they have accumulated plenty of interesting content, we don't know about the majority of them.  Thanks to Google, WordPress, <em>et al</em> we can find every attempt at introspective writing in the blog format, which skews the results a bit.  Let this serve as the introduction and let us agree never to write the second type of post: either by filling these virtual pages or by never apologizing for not doing so.

<img src="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/2296_1092202147934_2064_n.jpg" alt="Where the story begins." />

This picture is where I want to start our story.  What a happy bunch of people we are!  I'm the fellow in the center with a white bow tie and Joy is standing next to me looking especially radiant.  It's been <a href="http://fivesecondreview.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/a-person-joy/" title="My tribute to Joy.">10 years</a> and she looks even better today.  I want you to hang onto this picture in your mind, since it's real and true and a foretaste of glory.  We are in a church, surrounded by friends, before God, Joy just became my wife, and I just became her husband.  From here on out, we are, to use the Biblical metaphor, one flesh.

It's a mystery really.  God grants married people a special connection whether you know Him or not.  I admit that I've lost sight of the picture at time, but somehow God did not let me drop out of our marriage.  If it were by force of my will or of Joy's, I don't think our bond would have endured.  I attribute the miracle of our marriage to God.  

<blockquote>
When a man is newly married, he shall not go out with the army or be liable for any other public duty. He shall be free at home one year to be happy with his wife whom he has taken.
&mdash;Deuteronomy 24:5 (<a href="http://www.esvbible.org/Deuteronomy+24/">ESV</a>)
</blockquote>

That was our vision.  For one year, Joy and I would enjoy each other.  After that, life would begin for us.  We honeymooned on Catalina (with plans for Spain when we had saved up), we rented a dumpy little two-bedroom guest house, we bought a wonderful bed, we went out to eat as a couple on Saturday mornings.  Joy got a temp job that had real potential to become full time.  I starting riding my bike to work, which was busy and challenging and fun.  The past was fading and the future was hazy but hopeful.

Then we discovered that despite waiting until marriage to have sex (exceedingly difficult) and using effective birth control, Joy was pregnant.  It was at this moment that I discovered that my picture of marriage was all wrong.  Joy had deep struggles that I had never explored.  <strong><em>I</em></strong> had deep struggles that I had never explored.  What sounds lovely in theory (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uIuAFBRyjj4">two hearts beat as one</a>), turns out to be terrifying when you realize that:

<blockquote><pre>
The heart is deceitful above all things,
	and desperately sick;
	who can understand it?
</pre>
&mdash;Jeremiah 17:9 (<a href="http://www.esvbible.org/Jeremiah+17/">ESV</a>)</blockquote>

But for me and I hope for Joy, the best thing we could have done with our lives is to commit our deceitful hearts to each other.  My sick heart wasn't getting healthier on it's own.  There's little doubt in my mind that without Joy, I would have sunk into a comfortable, but deadly bubble of my own making.  She's the one who talked me into trusting God more than myself.  She's the one who convinced me that I can't serve God expect in the context of the church.  She's the one who asked me to confront my calcifying heart.  And if you ask her, I had similar effects on her.  The best part about marriage isn't that we are right for each other, but that we are wrong for each other in just the right ways.

My story will (probably) wander into happier times and if you don't happen to be happy yourself at the moment, that might be painful for you.  But know that human happiness has <em>never</em> depended on humanity.  Rather we are happy at times <em>despite</em> our desperately sick hearts.  

<em>Further up and further in!</em>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-08-22 16:19:36</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-22 16:19:36</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>hello-world</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>About</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/about/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 16:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?page_id=2</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[This is an example of a page. Unlike posts, which are displayed on your blog’s front page in the order they’re published, pages are better suited for more timeless content that you want to be easily accessible, like your About or Contact information. Click the Edit link to make changes to this page or <a title="Direct link to Add New in the Admin Dashboard" href="/wp-admin/post-new.php?post_type=page">add another page</a>.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>2</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-08-22 16:19:36</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-22 16:19:36</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>about</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>When life gives you...</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=21</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 19:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=21</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Joy, more than anyone else I've ever met, knows how to pick herself up and make the best of a bad situation.  For most people, our situation before Joshua was born didn't seem particularly bad: we were healthy and newly married.  I had a stable job and sufficient income.  We were renting a two bedroom house in a good neighborhood.  Both of us had expressed interest in children, with our only difference being whether to try for three (my opinion) or two (her's).  It's a bit hard to see how this would be hard luck.

It certainly was hard for me.

So I began getting excited about what a child would do for our brand new family.  I started feeling comfortable with the idea of getting all the child-rearing out of the way before I turned 50 and being able to enjoy doing stuff with the grandchildren that would cause an older man to suffer physically.  Perhaps this wasn't our preferred plan, but it had some advantages we couldn't have prepared for.  As far as I was concerned, our future was in clear sight and I was ready for it.

But Joy was thinking about my dad's family:

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ericson_boys.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ericson_boys.jpg" alt="The Ericson Boys" title="Ericson Boys" width="595" height="413" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-30" /></a>

My dad is the one in the center wearing overalls and a sour face for some reason.  I also direct your attention to the distinct lack of females among the children.  The Ericson boys did end up with a sister sometime after this photo was taken, but she was adopted.  As it happens, I have three brothers and no sisters.  So naturally, Joy expected to give birth to a male baby followed by several more leaving her as the one feminine influence in our household.

They never met, but I'm guessing Grandma Ericson and my wife would have gotten on splendidly together.  Once you take away her depression era sensibilities, my grandmother had just the same blend of seriousness, exacting standards, and love of life that Joy has.  But more importantly, each of them believe in doing things The Right Way.  There's something admirable about having every excuse to slack off, but determining instead to do the best you know how.  For Joy during expectant-motherhood, that meant taking classes.

We signed onto the <a href="http://www.bradleybirth.com/">Bradley Method</a>, which is to <a href="http://www.lamaze.org/">Lamaze</a> what a triple espresso is to a decaf, soy iced caramel macchiato: hard core.  We met with several other couples in the waiting room of a chiropractor practice for 12 weeks.  We sampled trail mix and other snacks designed to supply a pregnant woman and her parasitic baby the nutrients they need.  We learned everything about becoming an exceptional parent from how to talk to nurses about your birth plan (which turns out to be more than just "Push!") to what sort of diapers to use (cloth).

I don't buy into everything we learned (water births seem crazy and vaccinations are an excellent risk to take), but I do think our society has some pretty screwed up ideas about pregnancy.  My impression is that many people see giving birth as a medical procedure to suffer through.  Women were having children without fetal monitoring, sonograms, epidurals and the like for as long as anyone can remember.   As a man, I probably don't have the right to say this, but as a husband and a father, I think it's outrageous that we are treating pregnant woman like ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>21</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-08-30 19:35:02</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-30 19:35:02</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ericson Boys</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=30</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 22:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ericson_boys.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>30</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-08-28 22:10:17</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-28 22:10:17</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>ericson_boys</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>21</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ericson_boys.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Ericson Boys]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Are you prepared?</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2012/11/24/are-you-prepared/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 07:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=41</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Let me be honest for a moment: I'm not really sure there are twins coming.  Sure, Joy is in the visually uncomfortable stage of pregnancy and I've seen ultrasound images, but that's just some strange observations to my lizard brain.  My rational brain has put together the pieces, but so far the main emotions I feel are concern for Joy and hope that Joshua will benefit from having some siblings to be partially responsible for.  So, to answer the question I put in your mouth, "No, I'm not at all prepared".

<img src="https://sphotos-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/308355_10151059622983106_104341140_n.jpg" width="500" alt='Baby "B" (a boy)' />

Our church had a shower for Joy.  I hung out with an old friend who was visiting from the bay area with his two daughters and my son at a park.  It seemed odd that Mike kept looking out for his girls to make sure they were safe, until I realized that that's what you do with toddlers and preschoolers.  In the next few years, I'm going to be worried about inquisitive youngsters wandering into traffic or falling off of park equipment.  At least with Joshua, I lacked the knowledge that I could successfully raise a child.

<img src="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/418778_10151059621978106_831736516_n.jpg" width="500/" alt='Baby "A" (a girl)' />

Now that we've gotten a bunch of gifts for the nursery and Joy's sister has painted the walls (pastel green and purple), it's been my turn to assemble Ikea furniture.  I recalled the preparations for Joshua and how everything seemed so safe compared to what my parents used.  The new changing table has even more heavy-duty braces and even heavier-duty warnings.  Industrial design can reduce, but not eliminate accidents.

This time, we are going to put earthquake straps on everything.  We hadn't done that enough with Joshua, for some reason I don't recall, and he nearly crushed himself trying to climb our dresser.  The only reason we avoided a trip to the emergency room, or worse, was that our bedroom in Pasadena was so tiny the dresser hit the foot of our bed.  We heard the crash and found him safe, if terrified, in a dresser lean-to.  You'd think he's learned his lesson, but when he was showing off the twins' dresser in the nursery this weekend, he pulled out all the drawers and the whole thing tipped over.  This time we can thank Jeni for more than just painting.

If, the good Lord forbid, Joy went into labor today, we'd be totally unprepared for that.  And paradoxically, we'd be as prepared as we could ever manage at the same time.  When our new additions come (and it hardly seems right to imagine what their coming will be like), we'll adjust.  ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>41</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-11-24 07:23:03</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2012-11-24 07:23:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>are-you-prepared</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Traditional Christmas</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=55</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=55</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[If there were anyone born to love Christmas and excel at giving gifts, it would be my wife.  She's perhaps the most thoughtful person around and she gets so excited about the one day a year we shower each other with gifts, she starts thinking about it in mid-June.  It's like 100° and we are on a road trip in the some south-west National Park and Joy asks me if one of my relatives would like something from the gift shop.  And it's a perfect choice for that person.  She has a real talent.  (Actually, she has <em>many</em> talents; each more useful and amazing than the last.)

I'm more of a Grinch and it has nothing to do with the size of my heart.  Rather, it has a lot to do with my birthday coming on November 30, which is always right after Thanksgiving and usually just before Advent.  My tradition is to not start thinking about Christmas until after my birthday has come and gone.  I figure there are already twelve days of Christmas <em>plus</em> the weeks of Advent, so why should there be an additional month of pre-Christmas shopping?  It just seems&mdash;excessive.

<img src="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash4/380825_4846246556698_1822389279_n.jpg" alt="All the Whos down in Whoville liked Christmas a lot..." width="300/" align="right" />

This year was a little different.   Joy did an especially good job of waiting until December 1<sup>st</sup> to put out the decorations and I had a really amazing birthday celebration.  Even so, I'd been singing Christmas carols since September!  Of course, that was because I joined our church choir this year.  For some reason, I wasn't sick of Christmas before it arrived.  Our celebrations seemed more authentic that usual&mdash;we are also waiting for a child (or two) to finally come.  As always we had two days of crafts on the same weekend, but this year I had fun.  (See the photographic evidence. ===&gt;)

So when it was time to get a tree, pull out the decorations from our garage, and start the baking rituals, I figured I was ready to have a good attitude.  Joshua and I went to Home Depot the day they delivered the first shipment of trees.  We passed up the noble firs and the short Douglas firs to go direct to the 9-footers in the back.  Our house is a split-level with a wonderful vaulted ceiling, so we need the tallest, fullest tree we can find.  There were only four or five specimens left, so we made quick work of picking one out.

In years past, I would have tossed the tree in the bed of my truck, but I sold it a few months ago.  In order to save time, shoved the tree in the back of the SUV like the Grinch did with the chimbly.  With a bit of old twine, I fastened the tail down.  Slowly and with care, we drove home and were almost there.  A speed bump first closed and then jerked open the gate snapping the twine.  Thankfully, we pulled up to the garage without losing anything (like my Rollerblades or the car seat bases or the tree).  After a few minutes with the saw, the tree was ready to be erected in record time. 

One problem: our giant, cast-iron tree stand was missing the three bolts it needed to hold the tree.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>55</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2012-12-25 06:41:11</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Things people say... (to the parents of twins).</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=73</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=73</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[My twins have been alive for less than a week and I'm already noticing patterns of speech people use when talking about them as opposed to singletons.  Even before they were born, the most common question to us was:

<blockquote>
Do twins run in the family?
</blockquote>

I'm not really sure what they hope the answer will be.  I expect they are anticipating a treatise on the various twins in my genealogy.  I suppose they might imagine that <em>I</em> am a twin.  If you go back far enough, I bet everyone has twins in their ancestry.  (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twin#Statistics">Roughly 3%</a> of births in the US are twins, which means about 6% of <em>people</em> are twins.)  Factors other then genetics play a large role in twinning.  At any rate, I've been told there are twins in our past, but not more than average.  My standard response has become:

<blockquote>
They do now!
</blockquote>

People love babies and it's been fun to see people look so surprised when they see we have <em>two</em> of them.  Naturally, the next question is:

<blockquote>Twins?</blockquote>

I get it.  There are some siblings that look awfully close to the same age and, of course, we could be pushing around babies that aren't siblings.  Even so, it tends to be more of a comment then a question.  Next is often:

<blockquote>Boys?  Girls?</blockquote>



]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>73</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-01-21 01:54:02</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Twins are only 1 1/2 as tough as singletons</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2013/05/07/twins-are-only-1-12-as-tough-as-singletons/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=77</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[So it's been a busy few months and this blog hasn't exactly been on the top of my list of things to do.  Here are three things I've been taking care of:

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/snorers.png"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/snorers.png" alt="snorers" width="595" height="262" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-79" /></a>

Actually, it's been so long I hardly recognize the twins and I can't tell right of the bat which is Kathryn and which is Isaac.  Most of that time, we've had only a few hours of uninterrupted sleep at night and Joy skipped her last semester of nursing school.  So it's been tough to raise twins.

But I want to reassure <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/babblecom/my-wife-is-expecting-twins_b_3141819.html">this guy</a> that it hasn't been a nightmare.  It's true I find myself coming up with excuses to stay at work so I don't have to change diapers (my duty when I'm home) and I know that the fall is going to be a challenge when Joy goes back to school.  But the good outweighs the bad.

And I don't think twins are so much worse than a single baby that a person should be thinking this way:

<blockquote>
As horrible as this might sound, we found ourselves wishing these twins away.

We considered a reduction for about 30 seconds. (That's essentially an abortion of one twin, not both.) If you thought that IVF involved playing God, a reduction felt beyond brazen&mdash;Machiavellian, even. Give us a reason, we thought, as we had the twins tested for genetic anomalies. None came.
</blockquote>

I recognize that if you had one colicy baby (as the author had) you imagine how much worse it would be with two.  Twice the misery, right?  I'm not so sure.  For one thing, <a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/colic/DS00058/DSECTION=symptoms">odds are</a> you won't have two colicy babies; it's more likely you won't have even one.  Our oldest son had a serious problem with <a href="http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/healthy-baby/PR00044">spitting up his food</a>, so it was a bit frightening when Isaac started vomiting.  As it turns out, Kathryn eats and digests like a champ, so it doesn't really add up to twice as much puke.  On the other hand, we can't enjoy her sleeping through the night since her brother wakes us up for comfort feedings a few times during the night.

Each baby is different.  One will be giving you a hard time just when the other starts giving you a break.  Even if both are making things hard, they are likely to do it in different ways.  That can be a relief actually.  When one child is screaming and refusing to be comforted, it's not so bad when the other one starts fussing&mdash;especially if it's easy to solve her problems.  To be honest, there've only been a few times when I wished we only had one child because two is overwhelming.  And those times would probably have been <em>just</em> as overwhelming with only one.

But the parents of twins have a not-so-secret weapon: <em>everybody is fascinated by multiples</em>.  It's hard to overstate how excited people are to see our babies and how easy it is to get help.  Early on, I was waiting in line at the pharmacy for some medication for them.  One of the guys behind the counter saw me with two car seats and called me to the front of the line.  We have constant offers for baby sitting from our friends.  My mother-in-law has come up almost every Thursday and Friday since they were born.  We've been busy, but Joy and I are also getting regular lunch dates for the first time in years.  I won't say these things wouldn't have happened with a singleton, but I'm pretty sure having twins has helped.

For everything that really is twice as tough with twins, there's something that is no worse because of economy of scale.  ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>77</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-05-07 00:21:53</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2013-05-07 00:21:53</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>twins-are-only-1-12-as-tough-as-singletons</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>snorers</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2013/05/07/twins-are-only-1-12-as-tough-as-singletons/snorers/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 22:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/snorers.png</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>79</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-05-06 22:00:23</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2013-05-06 22:00:23</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>snorers</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>77</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/snorers.png</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A read through of Roe v. Wade</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=85</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=85</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>85</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-06-08 17:48:15</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Invasion of the vampire babies!</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2013/06/21/invasion-of-the-vampire-babies/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=93</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[When new parents are ready to leave the hospital, they sometimes look like this:

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/going-home.png"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/going-home.png" alt="Going home" width="523" height="407" class="size-full wp-image-95" /></a>

In addition to a newborn's aptitude for sleep for the first week or two (they don't have much else they can do), parents are lulled into complacency by the wonderful nurses who swoop in to take care of their infant's every need.  When you get home, that job belongs to <a href="http://fivesecondreview.wordpress.com/2013/06/21/daddys-diaper-delivery-duty/">someone else</a>.  

Over the months, our daughter has regained her ability to sleep for long stretches.  Sure, she's regressed once in a while, but I'd put her up against anyone in her age class in a sleep off.  Our son, who wishes to remain anonymous for this post, has not.

A typical night includes the traditional delivery-of-the-babies ceremony:

<ol>
	<li>I finally reach <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slow-wave_sleep">slow wave sleep</a>.</li>
	<li>My <a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2010/01/quieting-the-lizard-brain.html">lizard brain</a> registers the sound of an impending threat.  Is that a carnivorous dinosaur I hear?</li>
	<li>No, I'm pretty sure that's a tea kettle.  Who left that on at this time?</li>
	<li>Maybe our neighbor bought a puppy who is whimpering next door.</li>
	<li>Ouch!  An elbow in my side notifies me that one of our children (who are we kidding: it's our male twin) demands attention.</li>
	<li>Somehow the covers on my side are untucked <em>and</em> shackling me firmly to the bed.</li>
	<li>I'm free, but I've stubbed my toe.</li>
	<li>The dino-baby is now seriously angry.  He always wakes up with a grudge against the world.</li>
	<li>Dirty diaper? Check!</li>
	<li>Somehow, I'm back in bed, Joy is feeding the baby, and I'm asleep.</li>
	<li>Oh please don't tell me my other child is awake too.</li>
</ol>

The next morning, Joy and I are drained from caring for our children.  But they are smiling and content.  For better or worse, this too shall pass.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>93</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-06-21 14:46:55</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2013-06-21 14:46:55</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>invasion-of-the-vampire-babies</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Going home</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2013/06/21/invasion-of-the-vampire-babies/going-home/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/going-home.png</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>95</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-06-21 14:00:50</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2013-06-21 14:00:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>going-home</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>93</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/going-home.png</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>My princess</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/15/my-princess/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=102</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[The other morning after Joy fed her, I snuggled with Kathryn and allowed myself to be charmed once again by her smiles.  As she looked up to me with total trust I thought, "I will not let you marry anyone who does not love you more than I do."  My little girl will grow up and become a woman of her own, God willing, but that doesn't mean I won't do everything in my power to guard her heart.  Obviously I want my sons to marry women as wonderful as my own wife.  But I want to <em>protect</em> my daughter.  She is my princess.

[caption id="attachment_105" align="alignleft" width="595"]<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kathryn_driving.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kathryn_driving.jpg" alt="My daughter is thrilled to be in the driver&#039;s seat." width="595" height="491" class="size-full wp-image-105" /></a> My daughter is thrilled to be in the driver's seat.[/caption]

I grew up in a house full of boys, so I know how we operate.  The male of the species needs to be put in a <a href="https://www.google.com/webhp#q=%22position+to+succeed%22&amp;safe=active">position to succeed</a>.  Being overprotective, especially before they learn to make their own mistakes, will produce devastating consequences.  After a fall, you gotta learn to stand up, dust yourself off, and try again.  This goes for boys <em>and girls</em>, of course.  But there are some mistakes you don't want children to make at all, <em>ever</em>.  And this is how boys differ from girls.

Most likely, you'll think I'm old-fashioned (or worse), but some things are more devastating to girl than boys.  Failed romantic relationships are just one of those things.  

<hr />

I actually wrote this months ago and didn't want to finish it. I figured the work I need to do to justify this view of humanity would require research and careful logical argument. But each time I look at my daughter, I know that no argument can ever convey my feelings for her and my desires for her future. There's just nothing more to write.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>102</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-15 00:09:05</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-15 00:09:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>my-princess</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_google_plus_publicize_failure</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[O:13:"Keyring_Error":2:{s:6:"errors";a:1:{s:21:"keyring-request-error";a:1:{i:0;a:5:{s:7:"headers";a:11:{s:12:"content-type";s:31:"application/json; charset=UTF-8";s:16:"content-encoding";s:4:"gzip";s:4:"date";s:29:"Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:09:06 GMT";s:7:"expires";s:29:"Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:09:06 GMT";s:13:"cache-control";s:18:"private, max-age=0";s:22:"x-content-type-options";s:7:"nosniff";s:15:"x-frame-options";s:10:"SAMEORIGIN";s:16:"x-xss-protection";s:13:"1; mode=block";s:14:"content-length";s:3:"134";s:6:"server";s:3:"GSE";s:18:"alternate-protocol";s:8:"443:quic";}s:4:"body";s:202:"{
 "error": {
  "errors": [
   {
    "domain": "usageLimits",
    "reason": "dailyLimitExceeded",
    "message": "Daily Limit Exceeded"
   }
  ],
  "code": 403,
  "message": "Daily Limit Exceeded"
 }
}
";s:8:"response";a:2:{s:4:"code";i:403;s:7:"message";s:9:"Forbidden";}s:7:"cookies";a:0:{}s:8:"filename";N;}}}s:10:"error_data";a:0:{}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/cp3OqbXoaP]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:7:"twitter";a:1:{i:26086984;b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Kathryn driving</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/15/my-princess/kathryn_driving/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 03:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kathryn_driving.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[My daughter is thrilled to be in the driver's seat.]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>105</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2013-08-05 03:29:25</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2013-08-05 03:29:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>kathryn_driving</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>102</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/kathryn_driving.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Good Friday</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/19/good-friday/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 21:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=118</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Yesterday, my brother Bob died.

We found out right after our Good Friday service, which is the sort of thing that tests your faith. It was a shock in the sense that Bob was a 22-year-old man who did not engage in the sorts of activities that endanger the lives of so many men that age. He died shortly after a seizure of the type he'd experienced (and took medication for) since high school. As my wife relayed my mom's message, the shock faded into dull regret and sharpened into grief. It's one thing to nod with the pastor explaining why the death of one man is <em>good</em> despite appearances and quite another to accept the death of a brother whose life seemed to lay primarily in the future.

I repeat, for my own benefit, that Bob was a man. To me, he will always be a boy.

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_usher.jpeg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_usher.jpeg" alt="Bob Ericson" width="595" height="883" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-119" /></a>

This photo was taken of him at my wedding when he was ten&mdash;the same age as my oldest son. We don't have many photos of him from that day since the photographer didn't know until later that he was my brother and not a cousin. Even to me, 18 years older than him, Bob seemed like a stranger that my parents brought into their house. When he answered the phone after his voice dropped, I always mistook him for my brother Dave. His steady approach to the world reminded me of no other than my brother Doug. As I write this, the guilt gnaws at me; I wish I'd gotten to know him better.

Was it good that Bob died when he did? By no means! Death is an evil we all face; death is never right or fair. Most of us are familiar with the verse that Bob is standing in front of in that photo. It ends with the sweet promise of everlasting life. Even so, I am angry with God that he took Bob from us. I am already dreading the days and weeks and months to come when dark thoughts and feelings will sneak our lives and steal bits of our memories of Bob. I worry that pain will overwhelm some of us who knew him. 

And yet, deep down, at the core of my being, I know that light will not entirely vanish from the world. After we follow Bob through the shadowy valley, we will find him not resting, but rejoicing over a full life well lived. If you knew Bob, do not seek out the darkness&mdash;it will come. Rather find the shafts of light. For myself, I will remember the backpacking trips we took together, the game nights and jokes, his accomplishments as a he grew, and the day I learned that I had another brother whose name is Robert.

Even on the darkest of days, dawn comes in the morning.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>118</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-19 21:50:45</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-19 21:50:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>good-friday</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/bMj9Pbeuo8W]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/sNOBd1MJlG]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>2</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[A death in the family | Taking a one and one]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email/>
    <wp:comment_author_url>http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/08/15/a-death-in-the-family/</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>207.198.101.77</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2014-08-15 18:11:01</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-08-15 18:11:01</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[&#8230;] around the internet (and eventually finding the press release), I was reminded of what I did on Good Friday: searching for answers I didn&#8217;t want to find. What I feared most last April as a brother was [&#8230;]]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1408126261.7261340618133544921875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>_elasticsearch_indexed_on</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>2014-08-15 18:11:02</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>1408126433</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1408126434.359921932220458984375;s:7:"message";s:48:"jlericson changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:9:"jlericson";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bob as usher</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/19/good-friday/bob_usher/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 19:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_usher.jpeg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>119</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-19 19:01:10</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-19 19:01:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>bob_usher</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>118</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_usher.jpeg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Bob Ericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Eyes on Zion</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/21/eyes-on-zion/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 08:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Today was a better day. For one thing, I started rereading <a href="https://affiliate-program.amazon.com/gp/associates/network/build-links/individual/simple-get-html.html?ie=UTF8&amp;asin=B002BXH5WU&amp;assoc_ss_ref=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fgp%2Fproduct%2FB002BXH5WU%3Fie%3DUTF8%26keywords%3Da%2520grief%2520observed%26qid%3D1398051833%26ref_%3Dsr_1_1%26sr%3D8-1&amp;parentASIN=B002BXH5WU"><em>A Grief Observed</em></a>, which reminded me that every mourning is as individual as every relationship. Somehow, that helps for the present, though I see danger in the future. For another, it helps to sing familiar words with caring friends who know that comfort often consists in a hug. And I had something productive to do: write Bob's obituary.

I found it to be a lot like writing a Christmas letter: hit the high points and keep it short. My wife and parents edited mostly by expanding on points I tersely outlined. One aspect my wife added was that he enjoyed <em>many</em> family road trips, a caravan to Zion National Park. It seems a shame to not tell about  that summer while I recall it.

[caption id="attachment_134" align="alignleft" width="595"]<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/narrows_zion.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/narrows_zion.jpg" alt="The Narrows, Zion NP August 2011 with Robert Ericson." width="595" height="892" class="size-full wp-image-134" /></a> The Narrows, Zion NP August 2011 with Robert Ericson.[/caption]

My parents and Bob drove their Tahoe from Virginia to Idaho via Minnesota. I don't know if they stopped at Mt. Rushmore, but the odds are good they did&mdash;it was a tradition. Meanwhile, Joy, Joshua, and I took our Tahoe from Burbank to San Francisco to Crater Lake to meet at the family cabin in McCall. We did the usual things: boating, fishing, reading, cooking on the beach, playing games until late, and so on. 

The highlight was an overnight backpacking trip to a Upper Hazard Lake high in the Rockies. It's a short hike, but it wasn't easy for my son or mom. Even so, we had great fishing and enjoyed a comfortable camp at the lake's drainage. In the morning, we had fish, hash browns, oatmeal, and coffee cooked on the campfire. Bob carried some extra weight for those who couldn't and proved an expert outdoorsman. 

One of my Tahoe's tires got punctured on the way down the mountain. Thankfully, we had a full-sized spare to get us to Boise, but my dad wanted to drive with us to make sure we didn't get stuck somewhere. We stopped and had a picnic somewhere along the Payette River. Joshua by this time had come to adore Bob, who was extremely patient with him. (This never changed by the way; Bob loved my son.) I recall doing a lot of car swapping so that they could spend time together.

As we left Idaho, we could not bear to part ways, so we caravaned to Salt Lake City. Along the way, I looked into my rearview mirror and wondered if Bob was having car trouble; he was slowing down. Meanwhile, in his Tahoe, they wondered if there was some emergency, since we seemed in a real hurry. When we compared notes at the Lake Bonneville rest area, the answer became clear: my speedometer was broken.

In the morning, we had Liege-style Belgian waffles at <a href="http://www.brugeswaffles.com/">Bruges</a>. Again, we didn't want to split up quite yet, so we decided to travel together to Zion National Park. Zion Canyon was formed by the Virgin river cutting away sandstone in dramatic narrow cliffs. During the day, all six of us hiked toward the top of the canyon on a path that followed the river. When the path ends, most people enjoy the cool water on hot summer days. But the adventurous may continue though a section called The Narrows. It is so narrow, in fact, that travelers must hike <em>in the river itself</em>. 

My parents opted to stay with Joshua playing on the sandbar. But Joy, Bob, and I pressed on. Fighting upstream as the Virgin River flows stronger between steep cliffs is strenuous. It's important to have a pole or staff to steady yourself and maintain balance. Many people turn back after a bend or two. But we persisted. Bob was strong and determined. In the end, he outlasted us and went a little bit further as we rested. Finally we turned back and learned that keeping balance was just as strenuous going downstream as up. Bob was not phased.

And yet, his body failed him in the end. Life is fragile and all bodies break down one way or another. Today, I looked toward the one hope we can lean on: that Jesus really did lead the way toward Zion where we will have new, resurrection bodies. ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>132</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-21 08:04:25</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-21 08:04:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>eyes-on-zion</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/9LTm3etU8dt]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/U2onGA1Dmx]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Narrows_zion</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/21/eyes-on-zion/narrows_zion/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 03:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/narrows_zion.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[The Narrows, Zion NP August 2011 with Robert Ericson.]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>134</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-21 03:42:24</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-21 03:42:24</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>narrows_zion</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>132</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/narrows_zion.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Narrows, Zion NP August 2011 with Robert Ericson.]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Unbelief</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/21/unbelief/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 23:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=144</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[People sometimes assume Christians believe in the face of rational thinking. For some, that may be true. But I find that my gut instinct is to disbelieve and only by reviewing rationally what I have discovered to be true do I believe. A simple experiment proves it for me. When I look at this picture, my instinct says that when I fly home tonight, Bob will meet me at the airport as he often did.

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_joshua.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_joshua.jpg" alt="Bob and Joshua, Feb. 2012" width="595" height="793" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-145" /></a>

But the rational, logical, controlled <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dual_process_theory">portion of my mind</a> tells me that he won't be there. I live maybe 90% of my life the same as any agnostic. It's only when I make a special effort that I am confronted with the truth. It isn't that I haven't thought about the evidence that I believe. Rather, it's because I haven't internalized the evidence enough that I often doubt.

I have no answers for my son today. I'll be leaving for Virginia for at least a week and my biggest worry is that he needs a father's embrace right now. He loves his uncle and I don't think he really believes Bob is gone. Most of the time, I don't either.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>144</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-21 23:33:38</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-21 23:33:38</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>unbelief</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/fqoRrAsmfNe]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/sCaEZH7am0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bob_joshua</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/21/unbelief/bob_joshua/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 23:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_joshua.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>145</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-21 23:19:45</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-21 23:19:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>bob_joshua</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>144</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/bob_joshua.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Bob and Joshua, Feb. 2012]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reunion</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/23/reunion/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 17:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=150</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[It turns out that coming home has been at least as much joyous reunion as somber remembrance. As you might expect, guilt worms it's way into even this. How can we be happy when there's a hole in the family? We rationalize Bob's empty seat by supposing that he's somewhere else and will turn up after dinner or whatever. I'm sleeping in his bedroom and I found myself looking at his books and CDs. Bizarrely, I worried that if I moved anything he might notice my snooping. All of us who flew in this week expected Bob would meet us at the airport. 

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dscn0217.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dscn0217.jpg" alt="Bob and brothers in Hawaii" width="595" height="446" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-151" /></a>

Even before last week, we had commented on the unusual number of people we knew who had died in the last year. In every case, I have no problem supposing that we might meet them in heaven. But not Bob. Maybe this will change when we see the body and bury it. But I suspect that when someone was as close as a brother (even 18-years younger) will be harder to internalize as dead that people who were less a constant in our own lives.  ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>150</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-23 17:32:40</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-23 17:32:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>reunion</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/VYjaxutUP4b]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/t3rlngP5r1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Brothers in Hawaii</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/23/reunion/dscn0217/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dscn0217.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>151</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-23 17:01:26</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-23 17:01:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>dscn0217</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>150</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/dscn0217.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Bob and brothers in Hawaii]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Irrepressible hope</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/24/hope/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 20:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=154</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Yesterday was largely dedicated to visiting Mary Washington, Bob's university. He had finished enough of his classwork that my parents will receive his degree in a couple of weeks. I keep thinking that the precise timing was pretty good, actually, as this is the last week of classes. So most students were still on campus, but they are certain to be dispersing soon. 

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2006-12-31-23-00-00-52.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2006-12-31-23-00-00-52.jpg" alt="Balloons for Bob" width="595" height="446" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-155" /></a>

I'd never been to Bob's school. I could see many of the attractions: There's a sense  of tradition without being overly traditional. A creek runs through the campus' lovingly manicured lawns. Music and art and learning permeate as do fun and games. Bob and his friends spent many evenings in the Underground, which is half coffeehouse and half foodcourt. It's close enough to home, but not so close that dorm living would seem wasteful. And it's small enough that a person could know most of the school. 

The university from the president and dean to his closest friends gathered at Ball Circle for moment of silence. A couple hundred students wrote notes and prayers on balloons that they released into the air. Wind caught them up and carried many into nearby trees. Popping balloons, sudden and surprising as firecrackers at New Years, cut through the tension. My dad called out, "They aren't ready to leave." But most drifted off to biodegrade (these were special ordered for the purpose) across the nearby countryside. A group chanted and shouted Bob's name. Hugs and tears and condolences and quiet conversations ensued. 

In the evening, his <em>a cappella</em> group, One Note Stand, performed their concert as planned. Before each number, one or two members told stories about their time with Bob. None of the stories were forced, each was different, and Bob would have blushed and smiled in appreciation. They presented us with his senior gift: a bucket full of fun (and somewhat bewildering) items and remembrances. The One Note hat was given to his girlfriend, Stephanie. The student government president and university president eulogized my brother. His rowing team presenting my parents with his blanket and a teammate spoke. Finally the cox from his freshman boat and his roommate reminisced about their time with their fast friend. (Bob had many people who considered him their best friend. Somehow, it seems Bob felt the same about each one.)

Michael Wang, his roommate of threeish years, was especially moving in his words, spoken from the heart, and seasoned with a certain grief and joy. Our family will treasure the portrait he painted for us. He became, in his goodness and flaws, a real person with us if only for a few minutes. My brother, Doug, had nothing left to add to the evening except our sincere thanks. 

But the person who truly stole the show was Bob himself. Almost from the moment I heard the news, I wondered who would take his senior solo. Who would sing Bill Withers' <em>Ain't No Sunshine</em>? The simple, obvious and weighty answer: nobody. Or, if you are like me, a phantom voice that might have been Bob's. In my imagination, he got through his solo, but not without some tears.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>154</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-24 20:23:47</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-24 20:23:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>hope</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/ba3KYMqHRoH]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/myzszZbofu]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bob's Balloons</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/24/hope/2006-12-31-23-00-00-52/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2006-12-31-23-00-00-52.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>155</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-24 15:54:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-24 15:54:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>2006-12-31-23-00-00-52</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>154</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/04/2006-12-31-23-00-00-52.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Balloons for Bob]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Eulogy</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/26/eulogy/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 03:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=161</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Today I gave my brother's eulogy. I've included the text I spoke from below and the video of the entire service. (My part starts at about the 18:45 mark.) It's been an exhausting, yet wondrous, day.  

[youtube http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7hmNo4krNM&amp;w=560&amp;h=315]

Bob was full of surprises. I had given up hope of another sibling just around the time my parents announced a baby on the way. Around the dining room table that night, we laughed and talked and cried with joy. Though we didn’t ask at the time, my parents had been as surprised as we were. Mom asked me to share this from her journal:

<blockquote>Sept. 25, 1991

Another marker on the road to baby: sonogram today. We saw the little guy yawn, saw his hand up above his head, saw his heart beat at 139 beats a minute, saw all four chambers and his kidneys, his diaphram, his stomach. I am not sure I saw, but the technician pointed out his fingernails—we saw his nose, his mouth, his beautiful hand, even a tiny foot.
… 
We need to get busy—shellac the bassinet, paint Doug’s room, paint the changing table, buy a car seat, a back pack, a front pack! We need to buy diapers, a few basic clothes, hunt up the snow suit—or get a new one.

We need to choose a name!

Robert Christopher? Norman, Leif, Joel, James, Michael, Joshua, Jacob, Charles Robin?, Gregory.</blockquote>



This, I think, goes to show: Mom’s first instincts are best.

Another surprise when he was born: Dad expected me to call all the relatives with details. I didn’t know it at the time, but 10 lbs. 4.8 oz must have surprised many of them; Robert Kristoffer was a large baby. But he was little to us boys. We nicknamed him Bob because Robert seemed too formal and Roberto didn’t fit him. Soon we were learning valuable fatherhood skills: changing diapers, holding the head steady, rocking to sleep, and giving a crying infant to Mom. In a way, Bob had 4 father-figures, not just one.

But soon we left the house to start our own lives; every four years like clockwork. And Bob became something of an only child. I do not think those years were so difficult since he was loved deeply and richly by Mom and Dad. Each summer and Christmas we brothers caught up with his growth. Faults and failings were part of his growing pains. One summer he ate nothing but white things: rice, bread, pasta. But he surprised us with new passions and talents: fencing, airsoft, board games, card games, video games, reading, football, rowing, Scouting, the outdoors, the environment, guitar, <em>a capella</em>, mission trips, South Africa, girls. This Christmas, my wife and I knew that Stephanie had become part of our family; only the formalities were missing. The baby of the family became a man and I hardly noticed until too late.

For every story about Bob you have heard this week, my parents were co-authors. God had given them a final chance to perfect the craft of parenting, and they excelled. We saw in their relationship with Bob a model of how to raise a Godly man prepared to leave and become a father himself. I thought at times that they had spoiled the boy… and I was wrong.

My own son surprises us often too. But it was no shock to learn that he loved Bob the best of his uncles. With a rich legacy of fathering, Bob himself cared for Joshua and always had time for him. He loved my children and Dave’s children and Doug’s children. He taught them how to light fires and put them out, to carry a loaded pack and set up a tent, to read stories and to wrestle, to work hard and to play harder. Bob demonstrated patience with my children that I often lack.

Just as we were not prepared for his birth, death took us by surprise. Who can doubt that it had a purpose? Who can deny that this life, this boy, this man was given to us for a reason? Bob’s life offers wisdom:

<code>Remember your Creator before the silver cord is loosed,
Or the golden bowl is broken,
Or the pitcher shattered at the fountain,
Or the wheel broken at the well.
Then the dust will return to the earth as it was,
And the spirit will return to God who gave it.</code>

I will not accept that Bob’s life was a tragedy. Good Friday had tragic consequences this year, but it will only become a tragedy if our sorrow fails to bring us to the creator of the places and people Bob loved so well. By all means, let us cry rivers for a lost child. But let us also tap into the wellspring of life that flowed through him.
]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>161</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-26 03:49:56</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-26 03:49:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>eulogy</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792696</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/Qm318kftK9v]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/yOz92MJjs8]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lonely</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/29/lonely/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 04:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=166</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[After several days with more relatives  than I could hope to catch up with, today was reduced to my parents, my brother Dave, and I. We all did some work in an attempt to return to normalcy. But I think each one of us had a moment or two when we noticed something (or rather someone) missing.

<code>
	How lonely sits the city
		that was full of people!
	How like a widow has she become,
		she who was great among the nations!
	She who was a princess among the provinces
		has become a slave.
</code>
(<a href="http://legacy.esvbible.org/Lamentations+1/">Lamentations 1:1 ESV</a>)

I'm not sure what else to write about in the grieving process. There are more stories of Bob and a few more moments of "institutional mourning" as Dave astutely calls them. But I miss my wife and children. I'm ready to go home, but I don't want to leave my parents alone. I bought a return ticket for next week, but I doubt the timing will be good no matter how long I delayed. We are in the long-haul of grief.

The story of Joseph (the last chunk of Genesis) keeps surfacing in my memory. None of us were quite so jealous of Bob and I know that my parents' grief will not exclude love and compassion for the remaining sons. However, there's something missing in the house and it will take far too long to work out what God intended from the loss. Future reunions do little to ease current suffering. Perhaps the trial of faith will result in even greater joy, but at the moment we can hardly hope.

There's even a measure of guilt from going back to regular, pedestrian tasks as if we deny Bob's very existence. Some of us have commented that at times the fourth brother seems almost like a dream we all shared. But there is the train set he never quite put back together and the papers he didn't have a chance to sort and the medicine he was scheduled to be taking today. All of these things will slowly disappear or scatter. Will Bob's memory do the same?]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>166</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-04-29 04:47:14</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-04-29 04:47:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>lonely</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/atAN5QbnDqa]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/4tqEZGR6dR]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anger</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/05/anger/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 09:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=171</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[I'm sitting near the gate at Dulles that will take me to Long Beach and all I can think about is that I miss my family on both coasts. That and the free airport WiFi has hijacked all of my tabs and <strong>why would they do that?!?</strong> Next to simple sadness, the most prevalent and enduring emotion of my grief has been anger. I've been angry with God, of course. But also with complete strangers going about their day oblivious to the fleetingness of life. And with the reporter who initially wrote that the circumstances around Bob's death were "unsuspicious" which is as suspicious a way to word the sentiment as can be conceived. And with the commenter who pointed out that odd fact. And with Bob for dying. And his doctor for letting it happen.

And I've been angry with nearly all of my family for reasons that are entirely obscure. I've nothing against them and a far as I know, they aren't angry with me. I'm at least irritated with just about everyone who wants to console me. And plain old outraged by those who don't. I'm even annoyed with people who surprise me with just the right word of comfort. Not to pull a pop psychology trick or anything, but I suddenly discovered this morning that I'm mostly angry with myself.

Bob's death is the very definition of an "act of God" and the only two people who warrant being angry with in this situation are Him and me. When I think of what I failed to do in life and what I've been tempted to do, I'm disappointed in myself. How could I have forgotten to give Bob one more hug before we last parted? How could I get excited that so many people started reading this backwater blog because I started writing about his death? Why don't I start writing about life while I can? And why didn't God give me more time with Bob? Just one more year would have made all the difference.

And now it's so tempting to add shame to my troubles. At moments like this, I praise God that in His mercy He gave us a model like King David:

<code>	Cast your burden on the LORD,
		and he will sustain you;
	he will never permit
		the righteous to be moved.</code>
(<a href="http://legacy.esvbible.org/Psalm+55/">Psalm 55:22 ESV</a>)

He didn't say "Cast your burden on the LORD, unless it happens to be anger with God". He said that the LORD with sustain you if you cast whatever burden you have on Him. This is the real reason I continue to write about my brother' death&mdash;as long as I write I'm putting my burdens out of my hands and into God's.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>171</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-05 09:59:05</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-05 09:59:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>anger</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/bQguFXUxsx3]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/kFPWUnpy6f]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>We really need both parents</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/10/we-really-need-both-parents/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 16:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=177</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[It's been so wonderful to be back home; I had more important things to do than write. But this weekend Joy flew to Virginia for Bob's graduation and Mother's Day. So there's going to be an important person missing from this picture:

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n.jpg" alt="Double changing table." width="595" height="392" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-178" /></a>

Now I don't need Joy for diaper changes (thanks Bob!), feedings, bedtime, or playtime. In a pinch, I can even pick out matching clothes. But I can't replace her nurturing qualities. She had to remind me that the twin's blankets were in the drier after a restless night without them. Joshua and I dropped the twins off at the nursery for choir practice without their diaper bag. I don't know how, but I bet if their mom had been here, this wouldn't have happened:

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/2014-05-09-11-59-57.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/2014-05-09-11-59-57.jpg?w=300" alt="Nursery mess" width="300" height="225" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-181" /></a>

This isn't to say I couldn't <em>learn</em> to pay attention to such things. But I don't have the instinct for them. Mothers do. From an early age, it's easy to spot women who are unfit parents: their children lack basic necessities. The nurturing parent tends to be better at remembering to do things like bring a snack for their toddlers. 

Dads are important too. We take out the trash. Men also serve an increasingly important need as a child matures. The ultimate goal of parenting is to create an adult who represents an asset to society. Fathers pack a metaphorical suitcase of necessities when a son or daughter heads off to live on their own. We include lessons on individuality, self-sacrifice, competence, confidence, and so on. (Mothers pack the actual suitcase.) It's not that one parent can't take on both roles and do it well. It's that there's a constant struggle between wanting your child to be safe and wanting her to be independant. 

Last night, I wrestled my boys. After she sized up the situation, Kathryn joined in too. Joshua is getting too strong for me to handle all three easily, but he was so gentle with the twins. They were having the sort of fun you and I have on a rollercoaster: a little bit of fear without a sense of real danger. Isaac in particular enjoyed testing his strength against an adult. It reminded me of the times I wrestled with Dad and Bob when he was a boy.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>177</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-10 16:50:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-10 16:50:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>we-really-need-both-parents</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/aNYkSg8fL2w]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/5mnZeYmzKM]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/10/we-really-need-both-parents/1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>178</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-09 00:33:49</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-09 00:33:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>177</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/1554485_10152065835078016_470657768829369776_n.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nursery mess</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/10/we-really-need-both-parents/2014-05-09-11-59-57/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 23:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/2014-05-09-11-59-57.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>181</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-09 23:23:35</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-09 23:23:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>2014-05-09-11-59-57</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>177</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/2014-05-09-11-59-57.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Thanksgiving</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=190</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=190</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[I've been thinking about the quintessential American holiday: Thanksgiving. I've complained in the past that Black Friday commercialism encroaches on the purity of the day dedicated to thanking God. But then I remember that we already spend most of the day watching football and eating a week's-worth of calories. We aren't exactly living up to the ideal Protestant holiday of yesteryear.

[caption id="attachment_196" align="alignleft" width="516"]<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/thanksgiving_grace_1942.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/thanksgiving_grace_1942.jpg" alt="Why aren&#039;t there any young men in this photo? Because they are all part of the war effort." width="516" height="384" class="size-full wp-image-196" /></a> Why aren't there any young men in this photo? Because they are all part of the war effort.[/caption]

]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>190</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-18 22:26:12</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>"The First Thanksgiving at Plymouth" (1914) By Jennie A. Brownscombe</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=192</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 01:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/800px-thanksgiving-brownscombe.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>192</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-16 01:22:07</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-16 01:22:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>800px-thanksgiving-brownscombe</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>190</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/800px-thanksgiving-brownscombe.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Thanksgiving 1942</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=196</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 00:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/thanksgiving_grace_1942.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Why aren't there any young men in this photo? Because they are all part of the war effort.]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>196</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-17 00:57:28</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-17 00:57:28</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>thanksgiving_grace_1942</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>190</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/thanksgiving_grace_1942.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Affection</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/18/affection/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=199</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Recently, the twins learned about affection. Or rather, they learned to imitate it. If I say the word "kiss", Kathryn will turn to peck me on the lips (complete with a wet "smooch" sound). Isaac, meanwhile, has adopted dozens of babies, which is to say, everything that he enjoys hugging he now calls "baby". Anything he enjoys holding and/or throwing is a "ball". Somehow his vocabulary (and development in general) advances more quickly than his sister's. They take turns with separation anxiety, however. This is Isaac's moment to throw fits when we hand him to strangers. 

<a href="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n.jpg?w=595" alt="Easter 2014" width="595" height="793" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-200" /></a>

Kathryn, however, remains our world-class snuggler. She clutches most anything with gusto: blankets, stuffed animals, Duplos, shoes (especially Joy's), her bottle, and, most gratifyingly, people. Joshua and I have tested how long she will cling to us without support. (We haven't timed her, but it's got to be close to a minute.) Our male twin can be convinced to snuggle too, if he's tired and nothing more exciting is happening. Yesterday, all five of us had a few moments of quiet together. Joy and I had brought the twins back to bed and Joshua flopped down between us. Very quickly, we devolved from that pastoral scene to a broiling bed of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jq4L5Cb40pk">zerberts</a> and laughter.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>199</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-18 23:36:26</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-18 23:36:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>affection</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/516pPNgrNJg]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/bB5dmBegbP]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Easter 2014</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/05/18/affection/10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 22:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>200</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-05-18 22:29:19</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-05-18 22:29:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>199</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/05/10260011_10152120516063106_7574116067412360777_n.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Closure</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/06/25/closure/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 16:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=204</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[For the most part, I've moved on with my life. I rebel against myself for saying it, but I hardly think about Bob any more than I did 6 months ago. The occasional reminder, such as LinkedIn emailing me about his anniversary at a summer internship, jerks me back into reality. Today is his burial, which pretty much marks the end of the formal grieving process. From now on, we will have fewer and fewer opportunities to remember thrust upon us. I'm left dissatisfied.

<a href="https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/bob-020.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/bob-020.jpg?w=595" alt="Bob and his namesake" width="595" height="879" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-205" /></a>

Yesterday, I talked with my parents about closure and what it takes to get it. Being settled, having an explanation of what happened, knowing where Bob stands, wrapping up logistical details, and so on seem to be part of what needs to happen. I guess. I really don't know since it hasn't happened yet.

After Father's Day, it rolled into my mind that we'll never see Bob's children. Before the twins were born, I remember morning for my future children, who I imagined would never be born. There will be no miracles for Bob. Not even the Resurrection will restore that lost future, as far as I know. I can only trust his joy will be complete even so.

Bob will be buried at Arlington in the plot that eventually my parents will share with him. It's not often that you can see into the future, but I can envision our visits to Virginia, which will likely now include a pilgrimage to the National Cemetery. Will that be good for closure? I don't rightly know.

Lately, I've been even more irrationally worried about death than usual. It's a sort of accessibility bias: an example easily comes to mind of a sudden, unexplained death, so it's easy for me to imagine people in my life dying unexpectedly. I'd like that habit to stop; I don't like being at the mercy of things out of my control.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>204</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-06-25 16:17:05</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-06-25 16:17:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>closure</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/TL7BqdwMH2D]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/kDHoVKUoPf]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bob and the past</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/06/25/closure/bob-020/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 12:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/bob-020.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>205</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-06-25 12:31:37</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-06-25 12:31:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>bob-020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>204</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/bob-020.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why is being physically with someone important?</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=213</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=213</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[I started this blog to write about my twins, but it's become more an outlet for writing about my brother Bob's death. I've re-read and listened C. S. Lewis' _A Grief Observed_. He starts the final chapter my saying that he's run out of composition books and won't go out and buy another for fear that he will never stop writing about the loss of his wife. I don't have the luxury&mdash;WordPress won't stop me from writing again. And I'm not done with my thoughts yet, either. With no time to pre-grieve (as people are mourned before death when they struggle with terminal illness), I've had to come to terms with losing Bob suddenly.

Lewis asked if wanting his wife back would be good <em>for her</em>. After all, we like to say that the dead are "in a better place", which implies that being back in this world is a <em>worse situation</em>. It doesn't take long to fall into an existential trap: if the dead are in a better place, what's the point of spending time in this world at all. Am I deluded by some primordial instinct to prefer people I love being near me whether or not it's the best thing for them?

<a href="https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n.jpg"><img src="http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n.jpg?w=595" alt="Joshua, Kathryn, Isaac, and Joy coloring." width="595" height="446" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-214" /></a>

As I sat in church last week listening to a sermon about Zacchaeus, I wondered why it was so important for a chief tax collector to see Jesus. It reminded me of going to [The Broadmoor](http://www.broadmoor.com/) in Colorado Springs to see Ronald Reagan. Somehow, it mattered that I could see the President with my own eyes even if it meant being lifted up my my parents. Somehow, in some mystical fashion, catching site of a famous person makes them real. I know John Lithgow and Jerry West exist more fully because I saw them in Westwood.

Having spent more time away from Joy this year then I have since we were married, it matters more than ever to sleep in the same bed with her. We can talk well enough with Facetime, but I want to have her sitting across the table from me. I want to be able to hug my children. Temporary separation  ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>213</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-07-28 08:49:24</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>together</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Family coloring time.</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=214</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 07:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>214</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-07-28 07:56:12</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-07-28 07:56:12</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>213</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n-e1406534327731.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Joshua, Kathryn, Isaac, and Joy coloring.]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_backup_sizes</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:9:"full-orig";a:3:{s:5:"width";i:960;s:6:"height";i:720;s:4:"file";s:52:"10517529_10203768252189440_6416899996374763939_n.jpg";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A death in the family</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/08/15/a-death-in-the-family/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 18:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=217</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first I heard of Robin Williams death it was from someone who thought it might be a hoax. While poking around the internet (and eventually finding <a href="http://www.marinsheriff.org/uploads/855.pdf" title="Marin Sheriff press release about Robin Williams' death. [PDF]">the press release</a>), I was reminded of what I did on <a href="http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/2014/04/19/good-friday/" title="Good Friday">Good Friday</a>: searching for answers I didn't want to find. What I feared most last April as a brother was to find evidence of drugs or suicide. Not because there was any reason to fear that, but when a person dies suddenly and alone in this day and age, we are conditioned to expect those things. </p>
<p>It's been a rough week for many Americans since we lost the man who breathed life into Mork, Popeye, Peter Pan, and the rest. Robin Williams gave us more happiness than we could ever give back. In the face of this death, we are all powerless. But this post isn't about Robin Williams. Truth is few people knew the demons he fought. Our efforts to dig inside his mind are wasteful. The one thing I venture to suggest is that he very likely did not know, in those final moments, that God loved him.</p>
<p>Yesterday my oldest son, who is about to enter middle school, was working on his <a href="http://www.praypub.org/god_country/family/god_fam_description.htm">God and Family award</a> for scouting. One of the exercises was write a litany like <a href="http://legacy.esvbible.org/Psalm+136/" title="Psalm 136">Psalm 136</a> where he was supposed to fill in a line about a time he felt unloved followed by the phrase, "God loves me no matter what!" And he couldn't do it because he always feels loved by God. As a parent, I have never felt so proud; nothing could be more important that raising a child who always feels securely loved.</p>
<p>Of course our job is not done. The world overflows with reasons for feeling unloved and he hasn't experienced a fraction of what conspires to destroy him. Many parents have lost their children to drugs, depression, suicide, and other evils after good starts. And we stand on the brink of adolescence where many parents have shipwrecked their children via unreasonable boundaries and nonexistent boundaries. Looking back on my own life, I don't know if I felt unloved very often before junior high either.</p>
<p>What makes Robin Williams' suicide so hard to accept is that the love and admiration of millions of people <em>just isn't enough</em>. My hope for people I love who struggle with depression is that the love of God just might be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>217</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-08-15 18:10:56</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-08-15 18:10:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>a-death-in-the-family</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_google_plus_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://plus.google.com/103709140039254375780/posts/ZUEHrodMm8k]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792694</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_done_external</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{s:11:"google_plus";a:1:{s:21:"103709140039254375780";b:1;}}]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_user</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[jlericson]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>publicize_twitter_url</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[http://t.co/XDWbRq4bOP]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_done_6792699</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_facebook</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_google_plus</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_twitter</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_linkedin</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_tumblr</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wpas_skip_path</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>4</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[UK]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>uwe.keim@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url>http://www.zeta-producer.com</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>212.87.131.182</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2014-10-07 10:05:09</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-10-07 10:05:09</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[I've also lost my dad to suicide, back in 1978, when I was 5 years old. Even today this is something that influences my life (and the life of my mother) in some ways.]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>7362254</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1412676309.687941074371337890625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"uwekeim";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>1412694250</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>_elasticsearch_indexed_on</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>2014-10-07 10:05:12</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>1412694250</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1412680012.587554931640625;s:7:"message";s:43:"Akismet re-checked and cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"uwekeim";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1412694250.05259609222412109375;s:7:"message";s:48:"jlericson changed the comment status to approved";s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:9:"jlericson";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>5</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Jon Ericson]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>jlericson@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url>http://fivesecondreview.wordpress.com</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>24.205.73.19</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2014-10-07 23:09:13</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2014-10-07 23:09:13</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for sharing. I can't imagine losing my own father so tragically and so young. 

I've found that telling my story brings out the stories of grief in others. I think it helps to know that even though our suffering is unique, we are not alone.]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>4</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>5232752</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>1412723353</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>false</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1412723354.00893402099609375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"jlericson";}</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>1412723354</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>_elasticsearch_indexed_on</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value>2014-10-07 23:09:14</wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hope for the hopeless</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=223</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=223</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[This afternoon, I listened to <a href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/juicervose/?utm_source=local&amp;utm_medium=treatment&amp;utm_campaign=daMost&amp;utm_content=damostviewed">an episode of Radiolab</a> about an amazing story about how Disney movies rescued an autistic boy into an independent life. It's a heart warming story. One critic <a href="http://www.davidroyko.com/lifeanimatedreview.htm">pointed out</a>, however, that it's an atypical story:

<blockquote>Another autism story worth telling, though less marketable, is 2009's "Boy Alone: A Brother's Memoir," by Karl Taro Greenfeld. Late in the book, which describes the ravages of a family's life with classic autism, comes a depiction of Noah, now a man established in a satisfying, "recovered" life, including a fiancé — a happy ending.

But it is not real. The next chapter begins with a reproduction of a heartbreaking report about the 40-year-old Noah, issued by the state institution where he lives. His brother writes, "I dreamed that happy outcome … as therapy, as a study in what if, as an attempted answer to the great question: what if Noah could talk? What if Noah were normal? What if? What if?"

Owen's tale is a version of such a "What if?" while Greenfeld's is the current fate for many individuals with classic autism.</blockquote>

So what should we say to people who realistically have little hope for an improved life? This isn't an academic question for me; every Saturday I visit men in jail who face addictions and long sentences. For many, it's going to get worse before it gets better. And for others, there may be no better. Most will need to work hard to regain trust of their spouses, children, parents, family, and friends. Many will never regain that trust even if they manage to become trustworthy. If we encourage them to work on those relationships, are we giving them false hope? Should we be realists and tell them they can never live up to the standards of their community, much less God's standards?

As a parent, I realize my work has just begun. One of the things I appreciate about my own parents is that they have never stopped helping me strive to become a better person. 
]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>223</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-10-14 20:52:23</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Breakfast with Santa</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=226</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=226</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[Last Saturday, we met perhaps the bravest man in America: Santa. The day started fairly typically as our twins served as stereo alarms. I roll over and mumble, "Guess we better get them up." Joy agrees, but I don't move a muscle. Kathryn and Isaac aren't screaming&mdash;just chatting loudly&mdash;so I don't feel any urgency. However, we face a logistical challenge analogous to an amphibious assault of a Pacific atoll<a href="#foot"><sup>*</sup></a>, so my wife climbs out of bed. It might be surprising to non-parents to learn "Breakfast with Santa" must be
preceded by a breakfast (milk and bananas) at home. 

<a href="https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/santa2013.jpg"><img src="https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/santa2013.jpg?w=595" alt="With Santa, 2013." width="595" height="397" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-227" /></a>

<hr />

<a id="foot"><sup>*</sup> We've been camping which is closer to preparing for D-Day.</a>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>226</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-12-08 01:13:12</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Santa2013</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=227</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 23:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/santa2013.jpg</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>227</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2014-12-07 23:35:44</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2014-12-07 23:35:44</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>santa2013</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>226</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <wp:attachment_url>https://taking1and1.files.wordpress.com/2014/12/santa2013.jpg</wp:attachment_url>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[With Santa, 2013.]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Age of Maturity</title>
  <link>https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=232</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>jlericson</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://taking1and1.wordpress.com/?p=232</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[A few weeks ago, a pair of nicely dressed young men knocked on our door. They noticed our doormat, which reads:

<blockquote>
As for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.
&mdash;Joshua 24:15
</blockquote>

So we quickly fell into a conversation about Christianity. As we talked, I became impressed with their confident answers to my questions. "This," I thought, "is what I want for my children: to be able to answer difficult questions confidently."

A little later, the conversation turned to prophets. So I brought up Jeremiah who confronted false prophets. When a prophet speaks good news, ]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>232</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2015-03-07 06:31:51</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name/>
  <wp:status>draft</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[5232752]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>geo_public</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
